On Friday, OpenAI dropped their latest
model GPT6 Astra. And once again, the
benchmarks are insane. Astra handles
computer tasks better than Saul in about
half the time. It scored 99.9% on
OpenAI's Arc AGI benchmark, and it's the
first OpenAI model to reach their
critical threshold for cyber security
capability. So naturally, AI stocks
should all go to the moon, right?
Because for the last few years, the AI
trade has been pretty simple. Better AI
needs more chips, more memory, more data
centers, and more power. Except Astra
isn't just better, it's more efficient.
And depending on what happens next, that
could be incredibly bullish for some of
the stocks that you own and really bad
for others. Today on Dumb Money, GPT6
Astra is here. Are you holding the wrong
AI stocks? This is Dumb Money Live.
Hey there, Dave here along with Chris
and Jordan. We are Dumb Money. Welcome
to Dumb Money Live. We all We all know
that Astra is 100% capable of just
watching YouTube for you. Uh but you
probably forgot to prompt it to uh
prompt it to smash the like button. So
go ahead and do that for us this
morning. Chris Jordan, we are back on
track backto-back episodes because we
need to regroup on what might just be
the biggest mistake investors could make
on this new GPT6.
Being right about the technology, being
wrong about the stocks. Chris, I know
that you posted on X yesterday that GPT6
Astra is quote simultaneously far more
capable and efficient than expected, yet
still far from good enough. You said
that it's hard to imagine a more bullish
outcome for AI infrastructure. Explain
yourself.
>> Yeah, I think the biggest breakthrough
here with GPT6 Astra isn't that it can
do more, but it's that it can do more
with less. Right. So that's not actually
a bearish thesis for infrastructure.
That's what we've been talking about for
years now. Jebans paradox is actually
arriving in real time. Now the issue
though, guys, is that
Wall Street might just make the same
exact mistake they've made with every
one of these cycles. Um or they think
that falling costs per task actually
results in less AI spend. Um, again
there's two there's two sides to this,
right? Like what side do you fall on?
You know what side I fall on?
>> It's on the side where if AI gets 10x
cheaper, I think we're going to use a
100x more uh AI, right? And we've
already seen that once once Astra
examples started getting out there in
the marketplace. We saw that people are
now just leaving the the tokens are are
expensive but they're using less of them
and they're just leaving their computers
on and rendering a game for or uh you
know not rendering but having having
Astra build a game for them you know
over five days. And so it's it's a
different kind of it's a different world
where yes, it is more efficient, but it
just means we want to leave it running
longer and have it doing more for us.
>> Yeah, Jordan, I want to get your take on
this as an engineer. I've been reading
every qualified engineer's take I could
the last few days on GPT6 Astra. My one
big takeaway is that the big
differentiation with GPT6
is it essentially takes you from A to Z.
meaning it will really kind of take over
the the processes of determining
what agents you need, what agents need
to be doing at any point in time and
actually making a lot of incremental
decisions for you to get you all the way
down the path to Z, which is why we're
seeing so many really cool like zeros
examples where you just want something
and it does it. Now, there's a there's a
pro and a con to that, right? The pro to
that is it will actually give you a full
end result for what you need and make
the decisions along that path that it it
determines to be best as opposed to
waiting and stopping and waiting and
stopping which is a lot of what we see
um with anthropics uh AI latest AI
model. The negative on that is that I it
it it's not as great
as it relates to like, you know, doing
things ultimately the perfect correct
way, right? Like it's just going to make
a lot of guesses along the way. And so I
think a lot of people are having issues
with Astra really in terms of
controlling it uh in a defined manner
and working with it. you have to really
break it out into little pieces
otherwise it just it does too much right
like it does too much so I think there's
a learning curve here but as an
infrastructure trade what's most
exciting about this guys is it just goes
nuts with aentic AI like it it yes the
compute is like two and a is
meaningfully down like it can do like 3x
more with the same compute roughly is
what it feels like but the amount of
compute it's willing to take on to do
stuff it will just run with it. So, it
feels like one of these scenarios where
we're entering a new age of AI that is
just going to consume a tremendous
amount of compute more than we even
thought was imaginable and open up new
use cases. But it's not there yet, guys.
We're not there yet. Like there's so
much refinement that is needed on these
models that the infrastructure trade
just is in the perfect place right now
because we're so intrigued by Astro
about what it can do. And yet everything
that Astra is showing us it can do is
yet opening up more questions to
well we have an issue here, we have an
issue there, it needs to get better
here. So, it could do so much more, but
now we want it to like do so much more
than that because we see what it's
capable of, but it's not quite capable
of giving us a finished product that's
actually usable in any meaningful way,
okay? Or maintaining a product, uh, you
know, keeping up with a product. And and
so I know I'm talking all over the
place, but I just think this is the
perfect this is the perfect scenario for
the infrastructure trade. Like there
there's we've we've never been in a
better place for the infrastructure
trade than we are right now post Astra.
Jordan, do you get what I'm saying here?
Like have you been
>> I want to know if you did you have a
question. So like um I have thoughts on
this one. So did you listen to the DHH
DHH interview uh with Lex Freiedman? um
because he basically addressed all of
this already. What do you say? He's a
big user of AI. He's kind of come full
circle from being, you know, it's not
useful to it's supremely useful now. And
so he's gone through the whole, you
know, the whole uh spectrum of feelings
and emotions and usefulness of AI. And
he makes the point that um for
engineers, it's a it's tough, right?
Because the early models you would just
tell it what you want in a very specific
like you you'd line out exactly what you
want. I want functions to do this or I
want a class to do that. Um and uh you
could you could kind of wrestle the LLM
to do do those things. And you're right
with some of the newer models with
Astra, you need to let go and just let
it build. Um because it will do
as good of a job or a better job than
you would have done yourself, right? But
it's all about letting go, trying to
define less
um get less in the weeds and let the AI
run with the problem. Um and that's what
these models are designed to do. I I
think the best word for it is that the
models are tenacious, right? And so
they'll they'll attack problems in a way
that we haven't seen into completion the
way that we haven't seen them before.
Jordan, the counter to that is that I've
read that some of the ways that it
approaches kind of architecting the code
is whatever the fastest way to get from
A to Z, it's not always the most kind of
durable, bugproof, like sustainable code
base. And are you hearing the same
thing? like it's not that they're taking
a lot of like shortcuts uh which could
technically work to give you that end
product,
>> but it's just not the best way to go
about it to have durable long-term
code that's going to not break, right?
Or
>> on you know what kind of code base it
is. What are the concerns you have about
the code that it's producing? Can you
define and can you
can you then take that and figure out
what you need to define to to get it to
produce what you want?
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Um
>> so what you're saying Jordan is that
we're only a few days in. So yeah, like
in the raw it has weaknesses
>> and I think people need to change how
they're using
AI to develop software, right? uh it's
getting
um the techniques that you used for
previous models I think aren't going to
continue to cut it right and so you need
to learn to work within the models you
have
>> and on the AI development side it's like
every new limitation that we're finding
because it's doing more but as it does
more we're finding more quirks and
issues but every limitation is a
theoretical another like trillion dollar
incentive to keep scaling the models and
improving them with more compute
>> and more memory and more energy.
>> So the the deal with these models is
that they're built on you know uh as far
as engineering is concerned on all the
engineering work that people have
contributed to them and to open source.
Um and
that's why they're getting so much
better because they use all of this
stuff. But it still takes an engineer
to go through and make sure that it's
being things are being built in the way
that they should be built, right? So I
still you can b code stuff, but I think
you're going to end up with garbage. Um
I still think you need to have engineers
and real
>> technical eyeballs on projects you're
trying to build.
>> I mean every every iteration of new
models coming out makes you know it
gives it gives engineers something to
relearn what is the best way to use this
tool. Uh, you know, does anyone remember
hoarding uh hoarding the Mac minis
because of OpenClaw? That that seems
like a distant memory now. But this this
new version faster, more efficient, but
we're at GPT6. Imagine GPT12 or GPT 50
or 200. At some point, it's going to run
on some pure like pre-silicon raw sand
powered by the sun and ocean property is
going to be even more valuable. But
until that time uh and we're in a
postsilicon, post electricity, post AGI
or organic form, it's going to be
confined to some world where we're still
talking chips and memory and data
centers and power. And my thesis hasn't
changed on what is going to power all of
these versions of AI until we have some
major shift to a technology that doesn't
involve chips, memory, data center, and
power. Guys, is it insane that it was
like a few weeks ago when the entire AI
trade seemed to be unraveling because of
these open-source models coming out of
China? Could it had flipped more 180?
This is actually wild. The the way that
we go back and forth. I But just take a
moment here to realize that
>> this is going to repeat itself. If
you're an investor, you have to be
mentally prepared to understand that at
some point in the next few weeks, the
next few months, there's going to be a
new open model that's going to scare the
crap out of everyone and make you think
that OI and Anthropic don't have a shot,
right? before OI and Enthropic come
right back at you with an AI ASI looking
model that makes you think no these guys
have such a unique advantage that the
value of them is in the trillions of
dollars which is where we are this
morning with the what the uh new filing
for anthropic what two trillion and
people are saying two and a half
trillion is where we're earmarked for an
IPO right now I mean guys this is this
is this is what an insane time to be
alive as an investor do you know that uh
in San Francisco
I mean the housing is going out. I keep
hearing from people about the housing
prices up there because this anthropic
IPO I don't know if this is true is
supposedly bigger meaningfully bigger
like 3x bigger than every IPO in San
Francisco that came before it in terms
of the liquidity it's driving to
investors. We're going to have so many
wealthy people it's going to be
disgusting. This absolutely disgusting.
This is like a cultural moment and I'm
not saying it's great, not saying it's
good, okay? Where we're about to have a
lot of wealthy people minted here
between Anthropic and OI.
Dude, I don't know what this does for
society. Like, what do you think about
that? It's kind of
>> what is the uh the the average net worth
or the minimum net worth of a Nvidia
employee these days? Right.
>> Well, let me let me just tell you this,
guys. The the price of like the nicest
resort hotel room ever feels like it
went up from $1,000 to $2,800 or $3,000
in the last few years. I feel like if
you want to go to the nicest places in
the world, just expect to pay 5K a
night, 6K a night. That's what it's
about to be because you have the 0.001%
with infinite money. At this point,
these people have infinite money. Okay,
this is not about being worth this or
this or this. There is a relatively
large number of people in the next year
that are about to come into infinite
money. meaning they want to go to the
best places and they will whether they
spend 5,000 a night or$7,000 a night is
kind of irrelevant because they're all
worth hundreds of millions. Okay? And
they don't and they've never had money
before. So it's like it's guys this is
this is insane. It's absolutely insane.
It'll be interesting to see to see how
like for your example how resorts handle
that because there will there will be
this new infinite money class and then
there'll be everyone else. So
>> is it just that these exclusive places
are unable you you can't get in unless
you have unlimited money or like how's
it going to work? I want to be in the
private club where you have the
unlimited money.
>> I don't I don't know. But let's talk
about trades cuz there actually are
good. I I think listen
right now this could change and I think
if you're investing right now you got to
have eyes on the market you know every
few days to see what is popping up but
right now we are definitely in the cycle
of OI and Anthropic are real. They are
going to IPO more than likely at like a
$2 trillionish
range of value that supports basically
the entire infrastructure trade. Who are
the big winners here? I don't think you
get too fancy. I don't think you like
get speculative with your AI trades
here. If it's me, and it is me, and I've
made some trades today, I'm gonna zone
in on the near guaranteed winners from
this cycle. Okay?
>> So,
>> who Listen, I hate I I don't want to
talk about the same stocks all time, and
I am going to talk about a new stock
today. I'm going to talk about a new
stock that we have not talked about in
years. I promise. But before we talk
about that stock, I did up my position
again today in Amazon. And here's why.
In addition to Amazon being the By the
way, I read a report yesterday that
Amazon was moving up some of its uh some
of its supply chain for AI
infrastructure and increasing their
order sizes and accelerating delivery on
racks and everything else going into
their data centers. So I again am seeing
almost perfect visibility into what's
happening in Amazon right now and it's
awesome dude. I mean it's absolutely
awesome. I mean how is Amazon not Do you
remember the deal they just worked with
OI? Okay. What is they upped it to like
a hundred billion dollars dude uh of
infrastructure commitments from OAI and
they are they have a couple things with
OAI that are exclusives in Amazon
Bedrock now. I mean, what freaking
timing. Not to mention the fact that
Amazon, if they finish out their
investment, is going to have 50 billion
invested in OI with potential to do a
two to 3x that on an IPO. That's another
100 bill in cash, 150 billion in cash
right there. Uh now that Enthropic is
looking to be a viable IPO in the
near-term future at a two trillion maybe
two half trillion dollar price what does
Amazon have like eight or nine% of
anthropic you're looking at a couple
hundred billion dollars for Amazon from
the anthropic IPO we've been talking
about that also
um I dude I I got to own more Amazon and
I do I went in deeper on Amazon today
I'm just going put it out there. I went
in deeper. I'm starting to go I'm
starting to get more lever in Amazon and
I'm starting to get excited about it
again. So, on the negative side, okay,
we had a plane crash
perceptionally not great when it has
Amazon Prime on the side, but does it
but does it matter for investors?
>> Amazon actually doesn't operate the the
flight. you know, there's it's it's a
it's a branding problem. And and the
fact that uh it crashed into a bunch of
cyber cabs or or the didn't actually hit
them, I don't think, but the the way
that camera shot is set up and you see
the cyber cabs in the foreground and the
plane smoking in the background, the the
the uh third richest man's stuff just
crashed into the first richest man's
toys. my my favorite pick and I don't I
don't by the way people died here so
it's it's a absolutely
tragic tragic accident um but when I saw
those trucks that were right next to the
plane like 5 minutes after it crashed
and someone was joking that they're
getting package I'm like dude you never
know with Amazon that company is crazy
dude like I said I'm getting my
deliveries now in 20 minutes I it's like
magic I I cannot believe the stuff
Amazon is pulling off.
>> But there's a headline about Amazon
partnering with Qualcomm this morning on
custom chips for their data centers. I
mean, it's something every day. And
that's why I'm not playing Amazon for
day-to-day news. I'm playing it for the
long term. This is a this is a stock
that is going to be at the center of AI
for the foreseeable future.
>> Yeah. But if you look at what's
happening right now, if we believe in
the anthropic IPO, which means you
probably believe in the in the OIPO,
which will come after it. I've been one
of the very few people that have been
kind of neutral on OI for the last few
years going, "Hey guys, I know everyone
hates Sam Alman. I know this company has
some potential management issues there."
Uh, at the same time, you just can't
deny the fact that they've basically
been number one or number two most
downloaded app for two and a half years
globally on the iOS store essentially
every day for the last couple of years.
And like I don't know why people don't
understand that that is something that
happens like once every 15 years to a
company. and that the consumer adoption
that continues to happen with chat GPT
is unprecedented and astonishing. Okay.
And the degree to which people tend to
stay with a consumer app like that once
they're on it is way underappreciated.
We have a billion people that are using
Chat GPT aggressively throughout the
day. Lots of them are now paying, as we
know, $20 a month. Some of us are paying
$200 a month. And there have been times
where people like, "Oh, oh, AI's done
chat." Not anymore. Not anymore. Okay.
>> Every time a Every time another company
comes out with with some new fancy AI, I
always try it. So, I was on Grock Bot.
I've I was on Claude. I was on, you
know, I've gone all through all of them.
And it's kind of annoying because as a
consumer, I have I have to remember,
okay, I was having the conversation
about my dog's medication. Which one was
that? Was that Gemini? Okay. So, I have
to go find the conversation because it
knows stuff and it has relevant stuff to
me that I need to be able to have it
remember. At some point though, I
realize I keep going back to OpenAI. I
keep going back to whatever they have.
And so, it makes me want to give them
more information about me so that I know
it's all in one place.
>> I I want to stop experimenting. I think
there's information asymmetry and
arbitrage in the OI trade and everything
related to it because of investor
sentiment generally being really
negative the last couple years on
>> and OI. Okay. So like I think the
investing world just has blinders on
when it comes to OI. The investing world
wants to hate OI wants to hate does hate
Sam Alman maybe for very good reasons.
Okay. But it does not negate the fact
that OI with the ex with the exception
of a a period of time when Anthropic was
on fire with commercial accounts. Okay.
that OI has consistently
been in the leadership position
and now with what they're doing on the
on the commercial side of the business,
right? Like with with with their
enterprise product, they are now
definitely in a place that they could
theoretically go head-to-head with
Anthropic. And now Gemini and Google is
looking worse than it ever has. So it's
now looking like a essentially a
twohorse race for frontier models
between OI and Enthropic, a duopoly,
okay, of multi-trillion dollar
companies. And one of those companies,
quite honestly, both of them have bad
investor sentiment right now, which I
think is putting blinders on the fact
how good these guys are doing. It's
actually incredible. So
>> all AI has kind of a negative uh feel
though right now like it you have you
have Grock and and you have Elon there.
So I mean every every AI has a negative
sentiment and then the fear of losing
jobs uh and having your job taken over
by AI. So it's it's this kind of like
dance where if you if you are like me
and you see the potential for this, you
want to be involved as an investor
and not worry about losing your job
because you're going to you're going to
be in in the investor class.
>> But here's what's wild. If you really
want to go all in on OI,
SoftBank Soft Bank owns like something
like 13% of OI. Now Microsoft I think
owns you between 20 and 25% but it's a
much larger company. SoftBank has a
market cap of like $230 billion where
the OI stake is like roughly that
amount. Now now Soft Bank has debt but
they also own ARM. Uh they also like
it's a really inter I don't I think
SoftBank is it's it's a trade that I'm
not in yet, but it's a trade that I'm
going to spend a lot of time on this
week evaluating for the first time in a
long time. I'm really going to look
deeply at SoftBank. I already have
massive exposure into OI through Amazon
obviously and I have massive exposure
into anthropic through SKM South like
what it South Korean Telecom or
whatever. Uh which I still think is an
interesting opportunity here going to
the anthropic IPO because I think
they're like 20% of the company is
anthropic shares now. I don't know, man.
SoftBank is SoftBank is really
interesting. It I think it's
underappreciated here because everyone
just assumed OI was in trouble and it's
going to maybe take some time for that
to reverse. Now, if you look at the last
couple days, SoftBank has been up quite
a bit on this OI on this Astro move, but
you can make a case it should be up a
lot more just based on OI and the the
IPO that's likely coming as long as the
market doesn't completely
get destroyed by some new open model or
something happens right in the next few
months.
I do I do have a new stock trade though
on this and it's an interesting one. Um
>> Okay. Yeah, this is the moment we've
been waiting for. The new the new stock
pick.
>> Yeah, this is a company that we invested
in privately when it was a pretty small
company and then we all exited on the
IPO. Could can you take a guess what it
was?
>> Uh in g in gaming in gaming.
>> Oh yes. Yes. Uh what's what's the name
of that company?
>> Unity. Like you or something.
>> Unity guys. Okay.
>> What what is the biggest kind of like
use case that we've seen in the last few
days from Chat GPT Astra? It's been
oneshot video games which on the surface
looks really bad for video game makers.
But the key isn't that AI makes video
games. It's that AI is now radically
lowering the cost and the skill that's
required to basically create this
interactive type of environment, right?
And Unity actually owns one of the
biggest environments. All right, where
the agents actually go to build all of
this. And if you look at how a lot of
these games are being built right now
with GPT6,
a lot of them are going through real
engine or through Unity and like Unity
actually has an AI gateway that they
basically built so that codecs can
actually operate inside of the Unity
editor. All right. Um, so Astra is good
at is just getting in and using the
software on your behalf. It's not
creating the game out of thin air. It's
actually using software to do it. It's
it is its own computer. So I I I was not
thinking about the Unity play, but that
totally makes sense.
>> So I mean it does what people would do
and people would
>> write software to interact with the
gaming engine, right? Because that
engine is a lot of uh a lot of the work.
It's all the heavy lifting.
>> Yeah. The Unity editor is what's
actually like reading the project. It's
modifying all the scenes. It's writing
the code and it's executing the actual
like actions like like with codecs.
Okay. But more importantly, OpenAI,
okay, they actually
the Astro launch used Unity as the case
study. Okay. Like they actually used it
as the case study and with their like
integration through this company PLCO,
they reported 50% fewer manual fixes
versus GPT5.
Okay. Um again using Unity. So I think
one of my favorite GPT6 trades right now
has nothing to do with data centers
actually. I think Astra turns millions
of people uh that are gamers into game
developers. All right. And Unity kind of
becomes the picks and shovels layer for
AI generated worlds. It's a really
interesting trade. I haven't owned Unity
in a long time. I bought some today. My
position is moderate. All right. But and
the reason why is because historically
people think that this is a negative for
gaming companies. They think that people
are just going to use the frontier
models to make games end to end without
touching any other software layer. And
that's not at all what Astra does.
>> So maybe at some point in the faroff
future the frontier models will do
everything end to end on their own.
Maybe. But we're not seeing that today.
And right now, all I'm seeing is
a model that's going to meaningfully
increase the use of Unity and open up
Unity to so many more developers that
just were not in a position to code
inside of it prior to GPT6. So, I'm I'm
super excited for Unity and it's a new
position of mine starting today.
>> It'll be interesting to see how these
software companies start to charge. You
know how there's per seat kind of
subscription pricing? What if you have
like a hundred bots that are each named
something and have a different task in
your Astra or whatever GPT12 ends up
being?
Do they do they each have to pay for a
subscription? And is this going to help
other companies that are seatbased? I I
I saw people
or is it based on do do they take like a
cut u of the of the actual game revenue?
I I I'm not sure what they're
>> Jordan I almost think it's irrelevant
because that's like a business item that
if it's one way today they'll make it a
different way next month to adjust in
this AI world.
>> They'll figure out how to make money off
of it.
>> Yeah. I I just listen I I I think Unity
is really interesting here. I even
looked
>> so we just said Unity takes a cut and I
think that makes sense, right? You would
want people you would like as far as
incentives go, you'd want people
developing on the platform. You'd want
to hook them in and then you just get
you just take your your cut of the of
the gross when it comes to the game
revenue
>> completely. And I could even see Unity
eventually if you think about these
companies being valued in the trillions
of dollars, right? Um, okay. Let's just
let's just look at I I haven't even it's
been so long since I've really taken a
hard look at Unity. What what's the
current market cap on Unity today? It's
Oh my gosh, guys. It's 18 billion. You
have Real Engine and you have Unity.
Eight Real Engine was already acquired,
right? It's it's gone. So 18 billion.
Are you kidding me, guys? Is this not an
acquisition target for OI or for
Enthropic like or one of the big
>> frontier models, dude? They can
literally buy them for 30 billion. Not
even think about it. 35 billion.
>> Do they need to
buy?
>> I'm not saying
>> I'm not saying they they Okay, here's
the issue. Do they need to? No. Would
they potentially do it as a defensive
move against their competitor? Cuz
there's really only two big gaming Just
so they can say like, "Hey, the only way
you can develop Unity games using AI,
it's uh through chat now."
>> Yeah, I exactly. I think they might do
it as a defensive. I'm not saying it's
going to happen or even needs to happen,
>> but dude, I just I like it, man. I like
this concept of open worlds and figuring
out how AI eventually bridges us to that
place.
It it seems really obvious that
companies like Real Engine and Unity
play a critical role in that and they
become hyper relevant now for the f not
not that they weren't relevant a year
ago but they become a critical
>> gaming seems like it's ripe for
development because it's so boom bust
there are I mean just the amount of
money it takes to develop one of these
you know super high-end highly marketed
video games, the labor is through the
roof. And so, could you derip that by
using AI
to develop these games?
>> And I thought about this a lot.
Obviously, I'm invested long in take
two. Like, is this this the knee-jerk
reaction is has historically been bad
for gaming companies because anybody can
create games, but you can't. There's a
huge difference between building a
universe and actually operating a
universe or operating a game, right?
operating a game with millions of
players and functionality and
interconnectivity and like there's just
an immense amount of back-end work that
goes into that and I think the
beneficiaries here are gaming companies
where GPT6 and whatever comes after it
will meaningfully reduce the cost for
those gaming companies to expand their
universes and enrich them. Right? So,
when we think about, you know, GTA 6,
which we've talked a lot about the last
few weeks, and we think about how that
universe expands over the next 10 years,
leveraging AI, just think about how they
can expand the universe and and maintain
the IP of the characters, maintain the
like the community because like even if
you had a thousand different games that
were kind of just like GTA 6, you still
want people still want to be in the game
that others are in. They want that
connectivity with each other, right?
Like they want to buy into that kind of
communal IP uh that they have something
to talk about. It'd be weird if
everybody's playing a different game. I
maybe I'm wrong about that. Maybe we'll
go down a path where every human is just
in their own little world that's customd
designed for them. But guys, even if we
go down that road, I feel like that's
not happening in the next two to three
years. That's like five to 10 years out.
So I think in the short to medium term,
this benefits gaming companies because
it allows them to do a hell of a lot
more with less, right? So like, but it
it's not the knee-jerk reaction. So you
have to be careful. Like T2 opened down
today. Now they're about flat.
But
I don't know beyond that I would just
not get too fancy. I would think of the
obvious infrastructure players that are
also invested in these companies.
Amazon,
probably Microsoft,
uh Oracle. Okay. Oracle is so like
what's Oracle doing today? Because
Oracle is so tied in as we know to was
OAI, right? Like isn't OI like 50 or 60%
of Oracle's future buildout? And if
something bad happened to OI, Oracle's
completely
up shit's creek.
>> Oracle's up a couple percent today.
>> And today's such a nasty market day. I
feel that
>> it's a weird day for sure.
>> But but Iran, right? Like of course this
is going to happen and then we're going
to get into another fight with Iran,
which is what happened last night,
yesterday. And so oil prices are above
$100 a barrel, right? So again, net
short-term net negative for a company
like Amazon, which is what is also like
a bit of a headwind for Amazon today.
They had the the prime plane crash,
which overtook the news cycle the last
24 hours. Now you have oil over $100 a
barrel, historically bad for Amazon. Yet
that is like distracting the market from
the real story here, which is the
massive flywheel that Amazon has just
got even bigger. It's disgusting how big
it is now. I am so pumped to have Amazon
sitting where it is right now. I woke up
this morning and the first thing I did
is like, let's go. We're going deeper
into Amazon. That's what we're doing
today. Dave, did you say that flight
those flights aren't actually operated
by Amazon?
>> No, it's a it's a third party
flight. Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> I can't remember carrier
>> like A21.
>> I knew that they had talked about buying
planes. Do they own I'm sure they own
planes.
>> I'm sure they do, but this particular
flight was not operated by Amazon.
>> Okay.
It was just branded on the tail.
>> Just Just branded. Amazon paid for the
paint.
Yeah.
>> Oh my gosh.
Uh, hold on. Sorry. I'm having to send a
note here um to my wife.
>> Speaking of sending a note, did you uh
remember to uh post this episode on X?
>> Yeah, I did.
>> Oh, good. Good.
>> I got it during your opener, dude.
During your opener, too.
>> Perfect.
>> So, like for me, I added I added one new
company in Unity. I'm now starting to do
work, meaningful work on SoftBank as I
kind of assess the impending OIPO that I
think once Anthropic has a successful
IPO and I think they probably will, I
think the everyone's heads will
immediately go to OI and then they're
going to look for OI correlated
beneficiaries in the public markets,
which
Amazon's obviously one of the biggest
Microsoft is a big one as well obviously
and also SoftBank just is kind of like
SoftBank is the purest way to play OAI I
think right now and I think the market
will wake up to some of that so I'm not
in a huge hurry but I'm going to do some
work on SoftBank this week.
Uh those are those are kind of the three
things I'm looking at and then just kind
of like run-of-the-mill infrastructure.
You saw what happened Friday, guys. The
Friday trade showed us what the market's
thinking on memory, right? Memory's up.
>> Uh it's trickling up more today, but
Friday was the big memory move. I do
think we're going to hear more about
memory efficiencies
in the near term, but the market seems
to finally wake being smart enough to
realize that that's a positive and not a
negative for memory. Like it feels very
different this time. Remember when we
this happened with the open models,
memory just got tanked on that. Now OAI
comes out with a more memory efficient
model and memory goes up.
>> Like that's a very different
>> kind of like reaction than with the open
models. It's kind of stunning quite
honestly. So, if memory holds here the
next couple days, I think that's a
really positive sign that the market is
getting smarter as to like what is real
and what is just fear as it relates to
these variables that are hitting the AI
sector every few weeks. And I love I
love well, I mean, I say I love seeing
that. I love it, but I kind of don't
because it it results in less
inefficiencies.
where before the market just was making
dumb moves and if you had balls and cash
you can go all in and then the market
would eventually figure out that that
was the wrong decision
and those stocks would trade back up.
Now the market seems to be getting
smarter.
Uh which means there's probably a little
less opportunity, but investors are
going to be a little bit happier with
with less volatility every time we get a
news story that memory costs are coming
down or there's a new whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> Jordan, are you making
>> I I didn't realize that the market was
sideways to down today because Bloom is
up so much. my portfolio is is pure
green.
>> But Bloom, oh, by the way, Bloom is
again such a very clean, obvious
beneficiary of this, right? Like we can
have debates all day long about, okay,
memory is becoming more efficient. Maybe
memory stocks are tapped out. Maybe, you
know, Nvidia's GPUs
aren't as good as the TPUs that are
coming. I I don't know like that debate
can go on forever. The energy trade
seems to still be really clean
>> and not widely debated. So Bloom looks
great here. The only thing about Bloom
is it just has moved a lot, right? And
so people have seen this move before in
Bloom and they get scared. They're like,
"Wait a second. We went from 170 to 270.
I don't know. Is that 270 yet? Is it Are
we even close to that again?"
Uh 280 pinches at 280. Damn, dude. Look
at Bloom. So Bloom's up to 280. I think
investors have a knee-jerk reaction to
be like, "Dude, that's a big
move, dude. That's like a 70% move in a
matter of weeks. May maybe it corrects
here a little bit, but I love Bloom."
And and if it does, you know, any on any
weakness in bloom, I could see myself
kind of adding more. I love to see it,
though. This, you know, I went in deeper
on bloom when it felt I went in deeper
at the 170. I I all the way down. I just
kept adding bloom, adding bloom, adding
bloom, going it'll come back, and here
we are. We're back at 280, right? I love
this stuff so much, guys. I love the
inefficiencies in this market. I love
how dumb investors are right now. I love
how dumb Wall Street is. I love how just
like scared everyone is and how quickly
they get scared out of these trades,
man. I love this market so
much because if you actually do your
homework and have conviction,
you're just like and you're not freaked
out when these moves happen. They're
just opportunities. Every one of these
moves down is an opportunity. And like
we'll look back in a year and people
like, "How the hell do you get those?"
Well, I I just I believed in these three
stocks and every time they crash, I I
went in deeper. But you don't have to
like have these crazy
like undiscovered
like stock picks. You just don't need
them right now. You don't need to go
deep into speculative stuff, which is so
awesome because I hate that because when
you go deep into these speculative
names, it takes so little for them to
like get cut in half.
I don't think Amazon's getting cut in
half anytime soon.
So,
I don't know. Jordan, are you doing
anything differently as a result of GPT6
in the market? I'm curious what a
conservative
>> Not specifically GBT6. I mean, I'm um
I'm buying energy companies, right? So,
I bought Vistra um last week. Uh it's
been beat up so much and just grit
energy. I you know um
>> talk talk to me about Vistro. Like I
don't understand what's your take there.
>> It's just a it's just pure play power
consumption.
>> It it looks like that's a company that's
like pretty much flatlined. I mean,
they're all over the place, but
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Like are you just saying you just
love just general energy consumption?
>> I just don't think you can go wrong.
We're not going to use less energy over
time um with all of this going on with
AI and um
like energy.
>> So they're just like a moderate PE just
like
>> so boring
>> energy play.
>> So boring but okay. I mean I I get it.
That's so you. Uh anything anything else
that you're like
in meaningfully or changing up at all or
like adding to?
>> I've been adding to Amazon also.
>> Yeah, there we go.
>> Um Nius I went in so like during this
big drop that we had a few months ago. I
went into Nebius. I went into Amazon
more. Um
>> is it called Nebius?
>> I've been saying Nebius. Is it called
Nebius? No one knows. I call it Nius.
>> I don't I actually don't know either.
>> Yeah, I think it's
>> one of those stocks I read about but
I've never heard anyone talk about.
>> Um Yeah.
>> Um I asked I asked AI.
AI is like I I keep warning people like
be really careful if you ask AI what the
best stock picks are on something. It's
still like
I don't think it's great cuz like like
it didn't come up with Amazon as a top
five
>> trade on Astra and then I questioned it.
I said listen objectively don't give me
any crap here like be truthful. How are
you missing Amazon? I gave it my Amazon
thesis. I was like, it it it put
Microsoft up there. Um it put, you know,
Bloom, it put Nvidia, it put Crowd
Strike, uh it had Unity in there, which
was interesting.
It didn't have Amazon. And then it and
it was like, oh, dude, you're you're
totally right. It it's a top three.
Like, it's probably should be higher
than Microsoft as an astro trade. And
then it's like Amazon now has three
separate ways to win. Equity, they
invested 15 bill plus another 35 bill in
OI. Uh infrastructure obviously uh OI
expanded its AWS agreement by 100
billion over eight years including 2
gawatts of tranium capacity to OI huge.
Um and then of course distribution. AWS
is the exclusive thirdparty
cloud distributor for OpenAI Frontier.
Um, while Amazon and OI are jointly
building the stately agent runtime, I
don't know what that word means for
bedrock. Maybe Jordan knows what that
means, but and it's like, oh yeah,
they're definitely a top three. So, and
I I do agree with it. Amazon's my play.
I know it sounds boring, guys, but it
I'm happy to be in boring old Amazon and
levered up in it because I feel like the
closer we get to Amazon earnings, the
closer we get to learning just how much
all of this is benefiting Amazon. And I
just am starting to feel really good
that this next earnings report, although
it's still quite a bit away, what are we
like seven weeks away now from the next
Amazon earnings? I haven't been I don't
know
>> six or seven weeks. I feel like
the market just
>> I thought we just had an Amazon
earnings, wouldn't it?
>> It's been a bit. It's been
>> has it been a bit?
>> Yeah, it's been a bit.
>> Feels like I don't know feel like weeks
or days lately, you know? It just
doesn't Everything flies by.
>> I know, man. I know. It's
>> uh October 29th, so you're talking Yeah.
I mean, seven weeks. Seven weeks. seven
seven weeks away.
>> I think the closer we get to Amazon
earnings, the more people are going to
realize the inevitability of what's
going to happen on that day. And people
are like, "Wait, why did we trade Amazon
down from last earnings?" Like, I just I
can't get enough. I really can't. And I
and I love it. I love it that we're not
here having to pick all these
speculative stocks. By the way, I'm in
the whole AI infrastructure chain and I
do think generally Astra is positive
across the board. I just think there are
better and not so great. You know, there
are good and great trades here on Astra
and I'd rather be a little bit less
speculative.
>> So, you've gotten boring. Jordan's
gotten boring. I I don't have I don't
have a trade. I'm Amazon, Bloom, Tesla.
>> Uh,
>> yes.
>> The, uh, the energy play, Jordan,
>> although I'm in Micron also. I I bought
the dip on Micron. Have
>> Have you seen the, uh, the Vanguard
energy ETF returns year to date, it's up
44%.
>> Yeah. Well, so that's um Yeah, but
you're talking that you're you're mixing
in oil there, too. I don't I'm not long
oil right now. I'm just I'm long grid
power um through Vista. Uh yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean that's that's just all
related to the to the the conflict in
Iran.
>> Yeah. I I do think
>> which is great. It's just a different
trade, right?
>> Yeah. I do think that like I mean it's
going to be really interesting guys to
see how Enthropic plays out here going
into this IPO
even with
OI Astra really outperforming what
people thought it was going to be
capable of with GPT6.
I a lot of people I hear are saying,
"Hey, I still prefer the way that
Enthropic I'm able to work with
Enthropic like as as a developer. There
are certainly there's enough demand to
go around for both companies including
open models which we know open models
have been taking a decent chunk of
compute and that's okay because the open
models are taking the more repetitive
you know not so complex task. So, as we
can see, companies are basically taking
more of a broad approach in terms of
like, hey, we're going to utilize
compute and we're going to utilize it as
intelligently as we can.
>> I mean, does that even matter if you're
invested into an Amazon because aren't
people I mean, they're either going to
run them at home, right, which is just
terrible. Um, or you're going to put
them on the cloud, right? And so, invest
cloud infrastructure. My mind keeps
coming back to Amazon over and over and
over again because no matter how this AI
cycle plays out, no matter how big the
opensource piece of it is, and I believe
the most pragmatic kind of take on
everything that we've seen the last two
or three months is that it's going to be
a blend of open models and closed models
for for full frontier. Right. And so
that should really only matter if you're
heavily invested into open AAI or
anthropic or you know
>> what if you're
>> if you're invested in any of the the
Neoclouds or any of the um you know
traditional hyperscalers it it shouldn't
matter right where the
>> it really shouldn't happening
>> and and you know Jordan for the most
part like a lot of people that are using
things perfectly efficiently that are on
the bleeding edge that are able to
optimize every dollar that they spend
are very vocal about it especially on X.
But the reality is the global economy.
Okay. And the the the incumbent
companies of the world do not operate at
the bleeding edge of efficiency. Is is
that is that a safe assumption, Jordan?
meaning that they're probably spending
more money than they should on
everything including compute, including
the way that they kind of utilize
Amazon, right? And and everything else
that they do in the cloud. And so even
if there are
>> Well, you're also I mean you've got to
pay for experimentation too, right? And
so these companies are always
experimenting with different models.
>> Yeah, they're experimenting. They're
bringing like they're moving more of
their business into an AI world. So even
if there are tasks that are highly
repetitive that can now be done
meaningfully cheaper with compute
through an open model, that doesn't
necessarily negate the amount of money
that they also want to spend on a
frontier model for best-in-class
intelligence. Also, companies like
Amazon that are able to offer you the
full poo poo platter of compute from
cheap to best-in-class kind of win in
this scenario because you need to be
diversified and you need to try uh to
kind of split up the type of compute
that you use and companies like Amazon
can help you do that. So, it feels to me
like my head keeps coming back to Amazon
every single time. Um, also also, uh, I
think one of the things we haven't seen
yet because it's always kind of
splashier to show, you know, the entire
island of Manhattan getting replicated
in 5 days or a 3D world getting
replicated. But let's not forget
advertising, guys. Again, you can now
create the most immersive digital ads
uh with a singleshot prompt that is
going to massively benefit digital
advertising platforms of which Amazon is
the third largest in the world and I
think the fastest growing because now
advertising
quite simply gets better and more
accessible to more companies and more
people that want to utilize it. So, the
more accessible, highly immersive
advertising that's not just laser
targeted, but perfect for your product,
meaning you have imagine having like a
$200,000 video for your product on a $20
budget. I mean, you
>> from one photo you took with your iPhone
and then that that perfect beautiful ad
gets customized for each individual
viewing it. It's a It's a whole new
world of advertising, too.
>> Yeah. No one's talking about that yet,
but Amazon is in the pole position as a
beneficiary
of being able to offer all the world's
companies, which are pretty much on
Amazon, as they are also on Meta, as
they are also on Google. Those are the
three big platforms.
>> They're able to offer them
better performing
ads, right? which ultimately benefits
the advertising platform which is Amazon
because when your ad performs better,
you're able to spend more money on that
ad because it converts better. So kind
of it's one of those things where
everybody wins and no matter how you
look at the progress and traction of
these frontier models I think it comes
around to benefiting Amazon in every
aspect of its business whether the
infrastructure layer the chip layer the
digital advertising layer and of course
the one thing we haven't spoken about
yet
gosh guys are we not seeing such an
obvious end client uh uh uh uh real
value delivered to the end client with
these new models. It's becoming more
clear, which is the last hurdle to
showing us that companies like Amazon
are going to get massively more
efficient throughout the entire global
infrastructure chain uh leveraging these
this actual type of intelligence. Do you
know how many uh develop how many things
I've read this weekend from actual like
founders and chief developers that are
like this is so gamechanging in how it's
actually allowing us to identify
problems in our business right now and
actually kind of address those problems
just in 4 days in 4 days. So imagine
what companies like Amazon are able to
do across the entire chain of their
global business by bringing efficiencies
in to every and you know how Amazon's
all about efficiency guys. Could you
even imagine what's going on there right
now? Could you even imagine like what
they're doing right now to say, "Hey, in
two years, how much can we bring down
this $6 billion cost line using the
infinite intelligence that we have
access to?" And they have like 50 of
those budget lines. That's in the works
right now. And that's being massively
underappreciated by the market because
those are the things that all of a
sudden we're going to wake up in six
quarters and Amazon's going to be like,
"Oh yeah, the margins on our retail
business, the margins on our logistics
business are set to now increase by this
amount over the next few quarters
because of new functionality that we've
been able to deploy. first of all assess
and deploy due to the access to infinite
intelligence that we have as a company.
>> We'll start to see some return on that
capex they spent on building the
infrastructure and now their cost
structure is going down. Although
they'll continue having to build the
infrastructure indefinitely. But
yeah,
>> seeing efficiencies across the board
will be exciting with Amazon.
>> I agree. So anyway, in wraps, I got
three stocks here, guys, that you know,
one's new, one's old, one's potentially
brand new, but I haven't traded it yet.
And those are my Astro trades. Um, by
the way, that S&P inclusion on Friday,
Dave by on Bloom,
>> what a nice gift into the weekend.
>> What a nice
>> Oh, for sure.
>> I love it.
>> And another 10% today.
>> I love it, dude. I love it. All right,
guys. We might, if we can pull it off,
do one more show this week because we
have
something.
>> We have something to talk about.
>> Yeah,
>> we have a topic.
>> Yeah.
>> It's just are we actually able to do
three shows within
>> a week and a half or would that like
break the internet?
>> I don't know.
I'll just I want to close this whole
GPD6 thing out right now by saying that
if you're an investor, dude, this is
freaking huge, dude. This this is just
like I I think the biggest takeaway from
GPT6
is that we are so not only not done, we
are starting to really accelerate
on the AI side in terms of its actual
capabilities. Everything we were hoping
we would see which is doing more with
less is happening. And that's exactly
what the global economy needs to further
embrace AI. We the next big thing to
drop and I think we're now quarters away
not years away is this efficiency trade.
I think we are going to start seeing
uh big notations in earnings reports
about AI massively improving the
underlying business of so many of the
world's companies. And the second that
that starts to happen, we will get an
avalanche
of uh earnings revisions.
>> Yep.
>> And I think we will potentially see
meaningful multiple expansion across a
wide variety of companies that are not
in the AI world today. Like these are
not
>> AI trade becomes ubiquitous for all
industries.
>> Yeah. It's not something that
>> should happen, right? You should if you
have this, you know, if you have this
technology that's going to revolutionize
all of business inefficiencies and all
these things, then yeah, you should
start to see it across the entire
market.
>> So, I know we're a little ahead of the
next earning cycle, but if I'm an
investor, I am looking for those cues. I
am looking for mentions of the word AI
has saved us. AI has led to this margin
increase. It's reduced these costs.
It's, you know, allowing us to expand
into this new category. And I would just
count the number of times that you hear
that early in the earning cycle. That is
the alpha. That is the information
asymmetry. If you can catch it early
because if that starts to happen with a
handful of companies, I think that it's
an inevitability that it will start to
happen with hundreds of companies. And
when you start to see it happen with
hundreds of companies, you're going to
start seeing sellside banks, financial
media,
everyone saying, "Whoa,
we now need to kind of revalue
the global economy based on this new
world of AI."
>> And you'll start to see companies like
Vistra just selling a ton of
electricity. So
>> yeah, but Jordan, like yes, but like
Vista,
>> but no, this is like you. So look, your
argument about Amazon is my same
argument about about electricity, right?
And so if you think about what these AI
companies are selling, they're selling
the output of
um these GPUs, right? And how do they do
it? They do it by consuming electricity,
right? So it's the same it's the same
thing.
>> Fair. Fair. You're you're right. the
less sexy version and even less sex.
>> It's less sexy, but I mean that's the
that's the ultimate that's where all
these tokens get generated. It's it's
through, you know, electricity
generation
>> after I five.
>> So Bloom is one way to play that. Vistra
is another one. Bloom is the more
exciting one, but I think you know a lot
of the upside's been consumed on Bloom.
Maybe, maybe not. I think Vistra has
been beaten up. And uh if you look at
the amount of electricity even in Texas
that they're estimating that these data
centers will ultimately consume, it's
like double what we're currently
consuming.
>> I think the big question, Jordan, is
like if you develop a trade window
around it, when do you think the market
will come to terms with that as the
ground truth? Because if you look at
>> Yeah. No, I don't really care because
I'm not buying options. So, I'm just I
just own the equity.
>> Yeah. I just don't want to be in it for
years, right?
I get that that's not what you want to
do. I can do that and feel great about
it.
>> Yeah. But I want to make money like in
the next 90 days.
>> Yeah.
>> So, and I get it.
>> I'm patient on it. So,
>> that's fine. That's fine. I'm excited
about the next Amazon earnings even
though we're seven weeks away and I'm
I'm starting to prepare right now. So,
all right guys, I had a lunch. It starts
in like five minutes. I've I've got to
like I got to hop.
>> All right. Well, on that note, thank you
guys for watching. We're dumb money. We
will see you very soon.